Valerio Piotti

GitHub: ValerKoll

Email: valerio.uk@gmail.com | phone number: 07449.323.281

Summary

As an enthusiast software engineer learner currently enrolled at Makers Academy, I am keen to contribute my skills and passion to a team that values inclusivity, feedback, and continual growth. With a previous experience in engineering and 11 years' experience as a quantity and land surveyor across the designing field and implementation field, I have acquired my ability to prioritize tasks, efficiently self-manage workloads, and maintain reliable and consistently accurate data entry. I am currently developing good understanding and passion for test-driven development and an agile working environment. I am excited about the opportunity to bring my diverse skill set and dedication to learning to a dynamic team.

Technical skills

Languages: C, Python, HTML, PHP
Databases: SQL, PostgreSQL
Testing: TDD, VScode debugging
Version control: Git, GitHub

Projects

Project	Description	Implementation
Sailing Club Website	Managed and develop a non-profit project offering	HTML, CSS, PHP,
	boat experience at an affordable price.	Adobe FLASH
Video store database	Desing and implemented a fully functional database	Microsoft Access
	for a video retail store	

Education

- Makers Academy 2023- present Software development bootcamp focused on object-oriented design, Agile methodologies, test-driven development, and pair programming.
- University of East London BSc (Hons) in Surveying and Mapping Sciences.
- > Computer Aided Design for civil engineering, IFE institute, Italy
- ➤ 1 year Post-Diploma in computing, ENAIP, Varese, Italy followed by a 6-month internship at Digicom plc. Course core structure based on hardware-software integration using C, C++ and communication protocols.

Work Experience

Geocisa UK, London Euston St. – Surveyor From August 2022 to April 2023

- Carried out setting out, building survey, control network installation, and monitoring survey work at the Euston HS2 project.
- Worked with a team of professionals to ensure timely completion of projects.
- Developed excellent communication and coordination skills to work efficiently in a team.

Self-Employed Multi-Purpose Craftsman, London, UK From March 2021 to August 2022

- Great ability to read and interpret blueprints and manuals
- Exceptional written and verbal costumer skills
- Expert handling of equipment related to maintenance and repair work
- Thorough understanding of current health and safety guidelines

DYWIDAG-Systems, Slough, UK – Surveyor From October 2019 to March 2021

- Carried out setting out, building survey, control network installation, and monitoring survey work across all England.
- Developed expertise in the use of advanced surveying equipment and techniques.
- Collaborated with project managers and engineers to ensure accurate and efficient work.

Plowman Craven, London, UK - Junior Surveyor From January 2019 to October 2019

- Monitored building infrastructures and underground tunnels in Greater London.
- Assisted senior surveyors in carrying out building surveys.
- Developed strong problem-solving skills to tackle complex surveying challenges.

Full-Time student

From December 2017 to January 2019

- Science degree in Surveying and mapping.
- Subjects of study includes Programming and British Law framework.